export const quizData = [

    {
        question: 'Which one of the following is not a real time operating system?',
        answer: '2) Palm OS',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) RTLinux', '2) Palm OS', '3) QNX', '4) VxWorks'],
      },
      {
        question: 'What does OS X has?',
        answer: '4) hybrid kernel',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) monolithic kernel with modules', '2) microkernel', '3) monolithic kernel', '4) hybrid kernel'],
      },
      {
        question: 'In operating system, each process has its own __________',
        answer: '4) all of the mentioned',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) open files', '2) pending alarms, signals, and signal handlers', '3) address space and global variables', '4) all of the mentioned'],
      },
    
    
     {
        question: 'A square matrix [a] is neither symmetric nor skew-symmetric, and [a]T is its transpose. The sum and difference of these matrices are defined as [s] = [a] + [a]T and [d] = [a] - [a]T, respectively. Which of the following statements is true?',
        answer: '4) [s] is symmetric and [d] is skew-symmetric',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) Both [s] and [d] are symmetric',
          '2) Both [s] and [d] are skew-symmetric',
          '3) [s] is skew-symmetric and [d] is symmetric',
          '4) [s] is symmetric and [d] is skew-symmetric',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: "The square root of the number N is to be obtained by applying the Newton Raphson's iterations to the equation x¬≤ ‚Äì N = 0. If i denotes the iteration index, the correct iterative scheme will be",
        answer: '1) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = 1 / (x·µ¢ + N)',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = 1 / (x·µ¢ + N)',
          '2) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = 1 / (x·µ¢¬≤ + N)',
          '3) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = ‚àö(xi + N)',
          '4) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = ‚àö(N / xi)',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'There are two containers, with one containing 4 Red and 3 Green balls and the other containing 3 blue and 4 Green balls. One ball is drawn at random from each container. The probability that one of the balls is Red and the other is Blue will be',
        answer: '3) 12/49',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) 1/7',
          '2) 9/49',
          '3) 12/49',
          '4) 3/7',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'For the fillet weld of size ‚Äòs‚Äô shown in the adjoining figure, the effective throat thickness is',
        answer: '2) 0.65s',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) 0.61s',
          '2) 0.65s',
          '3) 0.70s',
          '4) 0.75s',
        ],
      },
     
      {
        question: 'Consider a reinforcing bar embedded in concrete. In a marine environment, this bar undergoes uniform corrosion, which leads to the deposition of corrosion products on its surface and an increase in the apparent volume of the bar. This subjects the surrounding concrete to expansive pressure. As a result, corrosion-induced cracks appear at the surface of concrete. Which of the following statements is TRUE?',
        answer: '3) Corrosion causes circumferential tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be perpendicular to the direction of the corroded reinforcing bar.',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) Corrosion causes circumferential tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be parallel to the corroded reinforcing bar.',
          '2) Corrosion causes radial tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be parallel to the corroded reinforcing bar.',
          '3) Corrosion causes circumferential tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be perpendicular to the direction of the corroded reinforcing bar.',
          '4) Corrosion causes radial tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will perpendicular to the direction of the corroded reinforcing bar.',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'The cross-section of a thermo-mechanically treated (TMT) reinforcing bar has',
        answer: '3) a soft ferrite-pearlite core with a hard martensitic rim.',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) soft ferrite-pearlite throughout',
          '2) hard martensite throughout',
          '3) a soft ferrite-pearlite core with a hard martensitic rim.',
          '4) a hard martensitic core with a soft pearlite-bainitic rim',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'For a saturated sand deposit, the void ratio and the specific gravity of solids are 0.70 and 2.67 respectively. The critical (upward) hydraulic gradient for the deposit would be',
        answer: '2) 0.98',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) 0.54',
          '2) 0.98',
          '3) 1.02',
          '4) 1.87',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'Likelihood of general shear failure for an isolated footing in sand decreases with',
        answer: '2) Decreasing inter-granular packing of the sand',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) Decreasing footing depth',
          '2) Decreasing inter-granular packing of the sand',
          '3) Increasing footing width',
          '4) Decreasing soil grain compressibility',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'For a sample of dry, cohesionless soil with a friction angle, ùúô, the failure plane will be inclined to the major principal plane by an angle equal to',
        answer: '4) 45¬∞ + ùúô/2',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) ùúô',
          '2) 45¬∞',
          '3) 45¬∞ - ùúô/2',
          '4) 45¬∞ + ùúô/2',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'A soil is compressed of solid spherical grains of identical specific gravity and diameter between 0.075 mm and 0.0075 mm. If the terminal velocity of the largest particle falling through water without flocculation is 0.5 mm/s, that for the smallest particle would be',
        answer: '1) 0.005 mm/s',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) 0.005 mm/s',
          '2) 0.05 mm/s',
          '3) 5 mm/s',
          '4) 50 mm/s',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'A watershed got transformed from rural to urban over a period of time. The effect of urbanization on storm runoff hydrograph from the watershed is to',
        answer: '3) Decrease the time base',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) Decrease the volume of runoff',
          '2) Increase the time to peak discharge',
          '3) Decrease the time base',
          '4) Decrease the peak discharge',
        ],
      },
      
      {
        "section": "a",
        "mark": "1",
        "question": "Anaerobically treated effluent has MPN of total coliform as 10^6/100mL. After chlorination, the MPN value declines to 10^2/100mL. The percent removal (%R) and log removal (log R) of total coliform MPN is",
        "options": [
          "%R = 99.99; log R = 4",
          "%R = 99.90; log R = 2",
          "%R = 99.99; log R = 4",
          "%R = 99.99; log R = 2"
        ],
        "answer": "%R = 99.99; log R = 4"
      },
      {
        "section": "a",
        "mark": "1",
        "question": "Consider four common air pollutants found in urban environments, NO, SO2, Soot and O3. Among these which one is the secondary air pollutant?",
        "options": [
          "O3",
          "NO",
          "SO2",
          "Soot"
        ],
        "answer": "O3"
      },
      {
        "section": "a",
        "mark": "1",
        "question": "The probability that k number of vehicles arrive (i.e, cross a predefined line) in time t is given as Œªt^k e^(-Œªt) / k!, where Œª is the average vehicle arrival rate. What is the probability that the time headway is greater than or equal to time t1?",
        "options": [
          "Œªe^(Œªt1)",
          "Œªe^(-t1)",
          "e^(Œªt1)",
          "e^(-Œªt1)"
        ],
        "answer": "e^(-Œªt1)"
      },
      {
        "section": "a",
        "mark": "1",
        "question": "A vehicle negotiates a transition curve with uniform speed v. If the radius of the horizontal curve and the allowable jerk are R and J, respectively, the minimum length of the transition curve is",
        "options": [
          "R^3 / (vJ)",
          "J^3 / (Rv)",
          "v^2R / J",
          "v^3 / (RJ)"
        ],
        "answer": "v^3 / (RJ)"
      },
    
     {
        question: 'Anaerobically treated effluent has MPN of total coliform as 10^6/100mL. After chlorination, the MPN value declines to 10^2/100mL. The percent removal (%R) and log removal (log R) of total coliform MPN is',
        answer: '1) %R = 99.99; log R = 4',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) %R = 99.99; log R = 4',
          '2) %R = 99.90; log R = 2',
          '3) %R = 99.99; log R = 4',
          '4) %R = 99.99; log R = 2',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'Consider four common air pollutants found in urban environments, NO, SO2, Soot and O3. Among these which one is the secondary air pollutant?',
        answer: '1) O3',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) O3',
          '2) NO',
          '3) SO2',
          '4) Soot',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'The probability that k number of vehicles arrive (i.e, cross a predefined line) in time t is given as Œªt^k e^(-Œªt) / k!, where Œª is the average vehicle arrival rate. What is the probability that the time headway is greater than or equal to time t1?',
        answer: '4) e^(-Œªt1)',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) Œªe^(Œªt1)',
          '2) Œªe^(-t1)',
          '3) e^(Œªt1)',
          '4) e^(-Œªt1)',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'A vehicle negotiates a transition curve with uniform speed v. If the radius of the horizontal curve and the allowable jerk are R and J, respectively, the minimum length of the transition curve is',
        answer: '4) v^3 / (RJ)',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) R^3 / (vJ)',
          '2) J^3 / (Rv)',
          '3) v^2R / J',
          '4) v^3 / (RJ)',
        ],
      },
    
    
    
     {
        question: 'Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence The official answered _________ that the complaints of the citizen would be looked into.',
        answer: '2) respectfully',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) respectably', '2) respectfully', '3) reputably', '4) respectively'],
      },
      {
        question: 'Choose the statement where underlined word is used correctly',
        answer: '2) He ensured that the company will not have to bear any loss.',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) The minister insured the victims that everything would be all right.',
          '2) He ensured that the company will not have to bear any loss.',
          '3) The actor got himself ensured against any accident.',
          '4) The teacher insured students of good results',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'Four cards are randomly selected from a pack of 52 cards. If the first two cards are kings, what is the probability that the third card is a king?',
        answer: '2) 2/50',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) 4/52', '2) 2/50', '3) 1/52 √ó (1/52)', '4) 1/52 √ó (1/52) √ó (1/50)'],
      },
      {
        question: 'Which word is not a synonym for the word vernacular?',
        answer: '3) indigent',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) regional', '2) indigenous', '3) indigent', '4) colloquial'],
      },
      {
        question: 'Mr. Vivek walks 6 meters North-East, then turns and walks 6 meters South- East, both at 60 degrees to East. He further moves 2 meters South and 4 meters West. What is the straight distance in meters between the point he started from and the point he finally reached?',
        answer: '1) 2‚àö2',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: ['1) 2‚àö2', '2) 2', '3) ‚àö2', '4) 1/‚àö2'],
      },
    
    {
        question: 'A column of size 450 mm √ó 600 mm has unsupported length of 3.0 m and is braced against side sway in both directions. According to IS 456:2000, the minimum eccentricities (in mm) with respect to major and minor principle axes are',
        answer: '2) 26.0 and 21.0',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) 20.0 and 20.0',
          '2) 26.0 and 21.0',
          '3) 26.0 and 20.0',
          '4) 21.0 and 15.0',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: "The relationship between the length scale ratio (Lr) and the velocity scale ratio (Vr) in hydraulic models, in which Froude dynamic similarity is maintained, is",
        answer: '4) V L r r =',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) V L r r =',
          '2) L V r r =',
          '3) 1.5 V L r r =',
          '4) V L r r =',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'Given cos x isin x i 1, the value of the definite integral, I dx is : cos x isin x',
        answer: '3) i',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) 1',
          '2) ‚Äì1',
          '3) i',
          '4) ‚Äìi',
        ],
      },
      {
        question: 'SO2 and CO adversely affect',
        answer: '3) functioning of the respiratory system and oxygen carrying capacity of blood respectively',
        section: 'A',
        mark: 1,
        options: [
          '1) oxygen carrying capacity of blood and functioning of lungs respectively',
          '2) functioning of the respiratory system and brain respectively',
          '3) functioning of the respiratory system and oxygen carrying capacity of blood respectively',
          '4) functioning of air passages and chest respectively.',
        ],
      },
    
    
      {
        "question": "Let $A_{ij} = i.j$ for $1 \\leq i, j \\leq n$ with $n \\geq 3$. The rank of A is __________.",
        "answer": "(B) 1",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
          "(A) 0",
          "(B) 1",
          "(C) n ‚Äì 1",
          "(D) n"
        ],
      },
      {
        "question": "A hydraulic jump takes place in a frictionless rectangular channel. The pre-jump depth is $y_p$. The alternate and sequent depths corresponding to $y_p$ are $y_a$ and $y_s$ respectively. The correct relationship among $y_p$",
        "answer": "(B) $y_p < y_s < y_a$",
        "section": "A",
        "mark": 1,
        "options": [
          "(A) $y_a < y_s < y_p$",
          "(B) $y_p < y_s < y_a$",
          "(C) $y_p < y_s = y_a$",
          "(D) $y_a = y_s = y_p$"
        ],
      },
    
    {
      "question": "A superspeedway in New Delhi has among the highest super-elevation rates of any track on the Indian Grand Prix circuit. The track requires drivers to negotiate turns with a radius of 335 m and 33¬∞ banking. Given this information, the coefficient of side friction required in order to allow a vehicle to travel at 320 km/h along the curve is",
      "answer": "(A) 1.761",
      "section": "A",
      "mark": 1,
      "options": [
        "(A) 1.761",
        "(B) 0.176",
        "(C) 0.253",
        "(D) 2.530"
      ],
    },
    

        {
            question: 'Which one of the following is not a real time operating system?',
            answer: '2) Palm OS',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) RTLinux', '2) Palm OS', '3) QNX', '4) VxWorks'],
          },
          {
            question: 'What does OS X has?',
            answer: '4) hybrid kernel',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) monolithic kernel with modules', '2) microkernel', '3) monolithic kernel', '4) hybrid kernel'],
          },
          {
            question: 'In operating system, each process has its own __________',
            answer: '4) all of the mentioned',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) open files', '2) pending alarms, signals, and signal handlers', '3) address space and global variables', '4) all of the mentioned'],
          },
        
        
         {
            question: 'A square matrix [a] is neither symmetric nor skew-symmetric, and [a]T is its transpose. The sum and difference of these matrices are defined as [s] = [a] + [a]T and [d] = [a] - [a]T, respectively. Which of the following statements is true?',
            answer: '4) [s] is symmetric and [d] is skew-symmetric',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) Both [s] and [d] are symmetric',
              '2) Both [s] and [d] are skew-symmetric',
              '3) [s] is skew-symmetric and [d] is symmetric',
              '4) [s] is symmetric and [d] is skew-symmetric',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: "The square root of the number N is to be obtained by applying the Newton Raphson's iterations to the equation x¬≤ ‚Äì N = 0. If i denotes the iteration index, the correct iterative scheme will be",
            answer: '1) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = 1 / (x·µ¢ + N)',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = 1 / (x·µ¢ + N)',
              '2) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = 1 / (x·µ¢¬≤ + N)',
              '3) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = ‚àö(xi + N)',
              '4) x·µ¢‚Çä‚ÇÅ = ‚àö(N / xi)',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'There are two containers, with one containing 4 Red and 3 Green balls and the other containing 3 blue and 4 Green balls. One ball is drawn at random from each container. The probability that one of the balls is Red and the other is Blue will be',
            answer: '3) 12/49',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) 1/7',
              '2) 9/49',
              '3) 12/49',
              '4) 3/7',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'For the fillet weld of size ‚Äòs‚Äô shown in the adjoining figure, the effective throat thickness is',
            answer: '2) 0.65s',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) 0.61s',
              '2) 0.65s',
              '3) 0.70s',
              '4) 0.75s',
            ],
          },
         
          {
            question: 'Consider a reinforcing bar embedded in concrete. In a marine environment, this bar undergoes uniform corrosion, which leads to the deposition of corrosion products on its surface and an increase in the apparent volume of the bar. This subjects the surrounding concrete to expansive pressure. As a result, corrosion-induced cracks appear at the surface of concrete. Which of the following statements is TRUE?',
            answer: '3) Corrosion causes circumferential tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be perpendicular to the direction of the corroded reinforcing bar.',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) Corrosion causes circumferential tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be parallel to the corroded reinforcing bar.',
              '2) Corrosion causes radial tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be parallel to the corroded reinforcing bar.',
              '3) Corrosion causes circumferential tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will be perpendicular to the direction of the corroded reinforcing bar.',
              '4) Corrosion causes radial tensile stresses in concrete and the cracks will perpendicular to the direction of the corroded reinforcing bar.',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'The cross-section of a thermo-mechanically treated (TMT) reinforcing bar has',
            answer: '3) a soft ferrite-pearlite core with a hard martensitic rim.',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) soft ferrite-pearlite throughout',
              '2) hard martensite throughout',
              '3) a soft ferrite-pearlite core with a hard martensitic rim.',
              '4) a hard martensitic core with a soft pearlite-bainitic rim',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'For a saturated sand deposit, the void ratio and the specific gravity of solids are 0.70 and 2.67 respectively. The critical (upward) hydraulic gradient for the deposit would be',
            answer: '2) 0.98',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) 0.54',
              '2) 0.98',
              '3) 1.02',
              '4) 1.87',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'Likelihood of general shear failure for an isolated footing in sand decreases with',
            answer: '2) Decreasing inter-granular packing of the sand',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) Decreasing footing depth',
              '2) Decreasing inter-granular packing of the sand',
              '3) Increasing footing width',
              '4) Decreasing soil grain compressibility',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'For a sample of dry, cohesionless soil with a friction angle, ùúô, the failure plane will be inclined to the major principal plane by an angle equal to',
            answer: '4) 45¬∞ + ùúô/2',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) ùúô',
              '2) 45¬∞',
              '3) 45¬∞ - ùúô/2',
              '4) 45¬∞ + ùúô/2',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'A soil is compressed of solid spherical grains of identical specific gravity and diameter between 0.075 mm and 0.0075 mm. If the terminal velocity of the largest particle falling through water without flocculation is 0.5 mm/s, that for the smallest particle would be',
            answer: '1) 0.005 mm/s',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) 0.005 mm/s',
              '2) 0.05 mm/s',
              '3) 5 mm/s',
              '4) 50 mm/s',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'A watershed got transformed from rural to urban over a period of time. The effect of urbanization on storm runoff hydrograph from the watershed is to',
            answer: '3) Decrease the time base',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) Decrease the volume of runoff',
              '2) Increase the time to peak discharge',
              '3) Decrease the time base',
              '4) Decrease the peak discharge',
            ],
          },
          
          {
            "section": "a",
            "mark": "1",
            "question": "Anaerobically treated effluent has MPN of total coliform as 10^6/100mL. After chlorination, the MPN value declines to 10^2/100mL. The percent removal (%R) and log removal (log R) of total coliform MPN is",
            "options": [
              "%R = 99.99; log R = 4",
              "%R = 99.90; log R = 2",
              "%R = 99.99; log R = 4",
              "%R = 99.99; log R = 2"
            ],
            "answer": "%R = 99.99; log R = 4"
          },
          {
            "section": "a",
            "mark": "1",
            "question": "Consider four common air pollutants found in urban environments, NO, SO2, Soot and O3. Among these which one is the secondary air pollutant?",
            "options": [
              "O3",
              "NO",
              "SO2",
              "Soot"
            ],
            "answer": "O3"
          },
          {
            "section": "a",
            "mark": "1",
            "question": "The probability that k number of vehicles arrive (i.e, cross a predefined line) in time t is given as Œªt^k e^(-Œªt) / k!, where Œª is the average vehicle arrival rate. What is the probability that the time headway is greater than or equal to time t1?",
            "options": [
              "Œªe^(Œªt1)",
              "Œªe^(-t1)",
              "e^(Œªt1)",
              "e^(-Œªt1)"
            ],
            "answer": "e^(-Œªt1)"
          },
          {
            "section": "a",
            "mark": "1",
            "question": "A vehicle negotiates a transition curve with uniform speed v. If the radius of the horizontal curve and the allowable jerk are R and J, respectively, the minimum length of the transition curve is",
            "options": [
              "R^3 / (vJ)",
              "J^3 / (Rv)",
              "v^2R / J",
              "v^3 / (RJ)"
            ],
            "answer": "v^3 / (RJ)"
          },
        
         {
            question: 'Anaerobically treated effluent has MPN of total coliform as 10^6/100mL. After chlorination, the MPN value declines to 10^2/100mL. The percent removal (%R) and log removal (log R) of total coliform MPN is',
            answer: '1) %R = 99.99; log R = 4',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) %R = 99.99; log R = 4',
              '2) %R = 99.90; log R = 2',
              '3) %R = 99.99; log R = 4',
              '4) %R = 99.99; log R = 2',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'Consider four common air pollutants found in urban environments, NO, SO2, Soot and O3. Among these which one is the secondary air pollutant?',
            answer: '1) O3',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) O3',
              '2) NO',
              '3) SO2',
              '4) Soot',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'The probability that k number of vehicles arrive (i.e, cross a predefined line) in time t is given as Œªt^k e^(-Œªt) / k!, where Œª is the average vehicle arrival rate. What is the probability that the time headway is greater than or equal to time t1?',
            answer: '4) e^(-Œªt1)',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) Œªe^(Œªt1)',
              '2) Œªe^(-t1)',
              '3) e^(Œªt1)',
              '4) e^(-Œªt1)',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'A vehicle negotiates a transition curve with uniform speed v. If the radius of the horizontal curve and the allowable jerk are R and J, respectively, the minimum length of the transition curve is',
            answer: '4) v^3 / (RJ)',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) R^3 / (vJ)',
              '2) J^3 / (Rv)',
              '3) v^2R / J',
              '4) v^3 / (RJ)',
            ],
          },
        
        
        
         {
            question: 'Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence The official answered _________ that the complaints of the citizen would be looked into.',
            answer: '2) respectfully',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) respectably', '2) respectfully', '3) reputably', '4) respectively'],
          },
          {
            question: 'Choose the statement where underlined word is used correctly',
            answer: '2) He ensured that the company will not have to bear any loss.',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) The minister insured the victims that everything would be all right.',
              '2) He ensured that the company will not have to bear any loss.',
              '3) The actor got himself ensured against any accident.',
              '4) The teacher insured students of good results',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'Four cards are randomly selected from a pack of 52 cards. If the first two cards are kings, what is the probability that the third card is a king?',
            answer: '2) 2/50',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) 4/52', '2) 2/50', '3) 1/52 √ó (1/52)', '4) 1/52 √ó (1/52) √ó (1/50)'],
          },
          {
            question: 'Which word is not a synonym for the word vernacular?',
            answer: '3) indigent',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) regional', '2) indigenous', '3) indigent', '4) colloquial'],
          },
          {
            question: 'Mr. Vivek walks 6 meters North-East, then turns and walks 6 meters South- East, both at 60 degrees to East. He further moves 2 meters South and 4 meters West. What is the straight distance in meters between the point he started from and the point he finally reached?',
            answer: '1) 2‚àö2',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: ['1) 2‚àö2', '2) 2', '3) ‚àö2', '4) 1/‚àö2'],
          },
        
        {
            question: 'A column of size 450 mm √ó 600 mm has unsupported length of 3.0 m and is braced against side sway in both directions. According to IS 456:2000, the minimum eccentricities (in mm) with respect to major and minor principle axes are',
            answer: '2) 26.0 and 21.0',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) 20.0 and 20.0',
              '2) 26.0 and 21.0',
              '3) 26.0 and 20.0',
              '4) 21.0 and 15.0',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: "The relationship between the length scale ratio (Lr) and the velocity scale ratio (Vr) in hydraulic models, in which Froude dynamic similarity is maintained, is",
            answer: '4) V L r r =',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) V L r r =',
              '2) L V r r =',
              '3) 1.5 V L r r =',
              '4) V L r r =',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'Given cos x isin x i 1, the value of the definite integral, I dx is : cos x isin x',
            answer: '3) i',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) 1',
              '2) ‚Äì1',
              '3) i',
              '4) ‚Äìi',
            ],
          },
          {
            question: 'SO2 and CO adversely affect',
            answer: '3) functioning of the respiratory system and oxygen carrying capacity of blood respectively',
            section: 'A',
            mark: 1,
            options: [
              '1) oxygen carrying capacity of blood and functioning of lungs respectively',
              '2) functioning of the respiratory system and brain respectively',
              '3) functioning of the respiratory system and oxygen carrying capacity of blood respectively',
              '4) functioning of air passages and chest respectively.',
            ],
          },
        
        
          {
            "question": "Let $A_{ij} = i.j$ for $1 \\leq i, j \\leq n$ with $n \\geq 3$. The rank of A is __________.",
            "answer": "(B) 1",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
              "(A) 0",
              "(B) 1",
              "(C) n ‚Äì 1",
              "(D) n"
            ]
          },
          {
            "question": "A hydraulic jump takes place in a frictionless rectangular channel. The pre-jump depth is $y_p$. The alternate and sequent depths corresponding to $y_p$ are $y_a$ and $y_s$ respectively. The correct relationship among $y_p$",
            "answer": "(B) $y_p < y_s < y_a$",
            "section": "A",
            "mark": 1,
            "options": [
              "(A) $y_a < y_s < y_p$",
              "(B) $y_p < y_s < y_a$",
              "(C) $y_p < y_s = y_a$",
              "(D) $y_a = y_s = y_p$"
            ]
          },
        
        {
          "question": "A superspeedway in New Delhi has among the highest super-elevation rates of any track on the Indian Grand Prix circuit. The track requires drivers to negotiate turns with a radius of 335 m and 33¬∞ banking. Given this information, the coefficient of side friction required in order to allow a vehicle to travel at 320 km/h along the curve is",
          "answer": "(A) 1.761",
          "section": "A",
          "mark": 1,
          "options": [
            "(A) 1.761",
            "(B) 0.176",
            "(C) 0.253",
            "(D) 2.530"
          ]
        },
        {
                "question": "The ultimate strength of steel in tension in comparison to shear is in the ratio of",
                "answer": "c) 3 : 2",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) 1 : l",
                    "b) 2:1",
                    "c) 3 : 2",
                    "d) 2 : 3",
                    "e) 1 : 2"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "The permissible stress for carbon steel under static loading is generally taken as",
                "answer": "c) 4000-4500 kg/cm2",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) 2000-3000 kg/pm2",
                    "b) 3000-4000 kg/cm2",
                    "c) 4000-4500 kg/cm2",
                    "d) 7500-10,000 kg/cm2",
                    "e) 10,000-15,000 kg/cm2"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "The property of a material which enables it to resist fracture due to high impact loads is known as",
                "answer": "d) toughness",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) elasticity",
                    "b) endurance",
                    "c) strength",
                    "d) toughness",
                    "e) resilience"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "A hot short metal is",
                "answer": "b) brittle when hot",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) brittle when cold",
                    "b) brittle when hot",
                    "c) brittle under all conditions",
                    "d) ductile at high temperature",
                    "e) hard when hot"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Guest‚Äôs theory of failure is applicable for following type of materials",
                "answer": "b) ductile",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) brittle",
                    "b) ductile",
                    "c) elastic",
                    "d) plastic",
                    "e) tough"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Rankine‚Äôs theory of failure is applicable for following type of materials",
                "answer": "a) brittle",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) brittle",
                    "b) ductile",
                    "c) elastic",
                    "d) plastic",
                    "e) tough"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "If an unsupported uniform cross sectional elastic bar is subjected to a longitudinal impact from a rigid bob moving with velocity v, then a compressive wave of intensity sc is propagated through the bar as follows",
                "answer": "a) vpE",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) vpE",
                    "b) vVvF",
                    "c) WpE/2",
                    "d) IvHpE",
                    "e) none of the above, where E = modulus of elasticity and p = mass density"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Tensile strength of a mild steel specimen can be roughly predicted from following hardness test",
                "answer": "a) Brinell",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) Brinell",
                    "b) Rockwell",
                    "c) Vicker",
                    "d) Shore‚Äôs sceleroscope",
                    "e) none of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Resilience of a material is important, when it is subjected to",
                "answer": "e) shock loading",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) combined loading",
                    "b) fatigue",
                    "c) thermal stresses",
                    "d) wear and tear",
                    "e) shock loading"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "In the case of an elastic bar fixed at upper end and loaded by a falling weight at lower end, the shock load produced can be decreased by",
                "answer": "a) decreasing  the cross-section area of‚Äô bar",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) decreasing  the cross-section area of‚Äô bar",
                    "b) increasing the cross-section area of bar",
                    "c) remain unaffected with cross-section area",
                    "d) would depend upon other factors",
                    "e) none of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Other method of reducing shock load in the above case can be",
                "answer": "b) to increase length",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) to decrease length",
                    "b) to increase length",
                    "c) unaffected by length",
                    "d) other factors would decide same",
                    "e) none of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "If a load W is applied instantaneously on a bar; then the stress induced in bar will",
                "answer": "a) be independent of ratio of mass of load W to mass of bar (y)",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) be independent of ratio of mass of load W to mass of bar (y)",
                    "b) increase with increase in y",
                    "c) decrease with decrease in y",
                    "d) depend on other considerations",
                    "e) none of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Brittle coating technique is used for",
                "answer": "d) experimental stress analysis",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) determining brittleness",
                    "b) protecting metal against corrosion",
                    "c) protecting metal against wear and tear",
                    "d) experimental stress analysis",
                    "e) non-destructive testing of metals"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Stress concentration is caused due to",
                "answer": "d) all of the above",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) variation in properties of material from point to point in a member",
                    "b) pitting at points or areas at which loads on a member are applied",
                    "c) abrupt change of section",
                    "d) all of the above",
                    "e) none of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "The endurance limit of a material with finished surface in comparison to rough surface is",
                "answer": "a) more",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) more",
                    "b) less",
                    "c) same",
                    "d) more or less depending on quantum of load",
                    "e) unpredictable"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Plastic flow in ductile materials",
                "answer": "b) lessens the seriousness of static load¬¨ing stress concentration",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) increases the seriousness of static load-ing stress concentration",
                    "b) lessens the seriousness of static load¬¨ing stress concentration",
                    "c) has no effect on it",
                    "d) depends on other considerations",
                    "e) none of the above"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "The maximum stress due to stress concentration in a bar having circular transverse hole, as compared to its static stress without hole will be",
                "answer": "c) 3 times more",
                "section": "A",
                "mark": 1,
                "options": [
                    "a) same in both cases",
                    "b) 2 times more",
                    "c) 3 times more",
                    "d) 4 times more",
                    "e) unpredictable"
                ]
            },
        
        
    ];
    